Guide to the Olaf Pitt Jenkins Papers, 1929-1973 (bulk 1946-1958)
Department of Special Collections
Olaf Pitt Jenkins Papers,
1929-1973 (bulk 1946-1958)
Special Collections M0531
Jenkins, Olaf Pitt, 1889-
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Olaf P. Jenkins, son of Stanford University professor Oliver P. Jenkins, earned his A.B., 1913, M.A., 1915, and PhD., 1930, from Stanford University. He worked for state geological surveys in Tennessee, Washington, and Arizona and held positions with several private companies. In 1929 he joined the California State Division of Mines and Mining, serving as State Mineralogist and Chief of the Division from 1947 to his retirement in 1958.
Scope and Content
This collection, dating from 1929 to 1973, largely relates to Jenkins' career with the California State Division of Mines and Mining and includes correspondence, biographical material, talks, and memorabilia. The bulk of the collection is correspondence concerning his appointment as Chief of the Division, 1947, and his retirement in 1958. Also included is Jenkins' memoir, 1973, of life at Cedro Cottage on Stanford's campus, where he lived as a child.
Access Terms
California. Division of Mines and Mining.; Stanford University--Cedro Cottage.; Stanford University--History.; Geologists--California.
Container List
- Biographical material, 1947-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Professional record (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, A-C (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, D-G (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, H-J (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, K-M (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, N-Q (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, R-Z (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Outgoing correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Outgoing Correspondence, January-February, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Outgoing Correspondence, March-August, 1958, and undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Letters of Commendation file, CA Division of Mines, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bibliography cards (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Directory of Consulting Engineers and Architects of the San Francisco Chamber of Commerce, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Mining and Metallurgical Society of America Newsletter, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Talks, 1929-1953 (Box 1, Folder 17)